Welcome back to an action packed time of of training.
액션 가득한 훈련 시간에 돌아오신 걸 환영해요
So now, after waiting about five minutes when I run this same, uh, list events function, we get
5분 정도 기다린 후에 이 리스트 이벤트 함수를 실행하면 많은 일이 일어나고 있는 걸 볼 수
to see lots of things going on.
있죠. Get it
What you see in the last ten events is that training is happening.
지난 10종목 동안 훈련이 진행되고 있어요
And you can see in this message the step zero, step one, step two, step three out of 500, representing
이 메시지를 보시면 단계 0, 1, 2, 3이 500개 중 하나입니다 500개의
the 500 different training data points that it's going to go through.
다른 훈련 데이터 포인트를 나타내죠
And you'll also see here training loss.
훈련의 손실도 볼 수 있어요
Training loss is something that we want to come down and that will show us, uh, a good outcome, which
훈련에서 진 걸 만회해서 좋은 결과를 내고 싶어요 그게
is of course, what we're going for.
우리 목표죠
And every time if I rerun this, we'll see now that it's already on step 118 as we go now, it's kind
이걸 재실행할 때마다 이미 118단계인 걸 보게 됩니다 지금 하고 있죠 무슨 일인지 보기가
of hard to see what's going on here.
좀 어려워요
And so this would be this would be a bit challenging if this is what we had to put up with.
비트 박스를 참는 게 쉽지 않았을 거예요 Put it up Put up Put it up Put it up Put it Put it Put it Put it Put it
But we don't because we use weights and biases and here, here is our gorgeous weights and biases screen
우리는 무게와 편향성을 이용하기 때문에 그렇게 하지 않습니다 여기 멋진 무게와 편향
which allows us to follow along with the training.
스크린으로 훈련 과정을 따라 볼 수 있죠
And what we can see is the the results of training loss and watch what's happening.
훈련에서 손실을 본 결과가 어떻게 되는지 볼 수 있어요
It's just updated because the page was refreshing.
페이지가 새로워져서 업데이트된 거예요
Um, and we'll get to see and get some insight into what's going on.
Get up! Get up! 어떤 상황인지 파악할 수 있을 거예요
Now, one thing that you'll always see when you're running this kind of training is that the first few
이런 종류의 훈련을 실행할 때 항상 보게 되는 것 중 하나는 첫 몇 배치 단계에서
batch steps will typically show a dramatic drop.
보통 극적인 드롭을 보인다는 거죠
Um, and that's actually not necessarily something to get too excited about.
get's get's get's get's get. 이건 사실 그렇게 좋아할 일은 아니에요
Typically, what's happening there is that the model is very quickly, uh, learning, um, the very
일반적으로 이 모델은 아주 빠르게 학습합니다 거의 말할 필요도
much the parts of the structure which almost go without saying, like the fact that there's a dollar
없는 구조의 일부를요 $ 기호가 있는 거나 소수점을
sign, um, and uh, and where to put the decimal point and a few other things that, that, um, I
어디에 둘지 같은 거요 이 경우에는 개념에서 0을 0으로 추정하는 게 다른
think in this case, it realizes that just guessing zero zero for the sense is more likely than, than
어떤 것보다도 올바른 센트 수가 될 가능성이 높죠 달러의 개수에는
anything else to be the right number of cents, because there's many things that are just a whole number
많은 것들이 있으니까요
So there's this is that's total speculation, but it's things like that, the kind of obvious stuff
아직은 추측일 뿐이지만 이런 것들이 도움이 돼요. Get-Tuck Season
about the construct that allows training to to come down very quickly for the first few steps to get
1 닙턱 시즌 1 이런 구조의 특징 덕분에 훈련이 빠르게 진행되고 첫 몇 단계에서는 특징을 빠르게
the obvious stuff out of the way, so that it's now following a decent pattern.
파악해서 지금은 괜찮은 패턴을 따르고 있죠.
What you're really looking for is continual progress from that point, and you typically, if you've
그 시점부터 계속적인 진전을 봐야 합니다 트레이닝 세팅을 잘 해뒀다면
got a training set up well and there's no right or wrong answers here.
여기에 옳고 그른 답은 없어요
So so there's exceptions to everything I'm saying now.
제가 지금 하는 모든 것에 예외가 있는 거죠
But but generally speaking you do want to see some variation.
하지만 일반적으로 보면 약간의 변화가 있어야 해요
It's good to see some some batch steps that have greater and lower loss because you are you're trying
손실이 크고 적은 배치 단계를 보는 건 좋아요 최적화하고 다양한
to optimize and you're looking to explore different, different possibilities.
가능성을 탐색해야 하니까요
Um, and what you're trying to what you're looking for is a kind of trend where over time, whilst any
지금 보시는 건 일종의 경향인데요 시간이 지나면서
individual batch step may go up or down, you do expect or hope to see a gradual decrease in loss,
배치 단계를 늘렸다가 줄였다가 하면서 손실이 서서히 줄어들기를
um, over time and as potentially a slight concern for us that might make us a bit worried, is that
기대하는 거죠 그리고 걱정되는 부분은 비트 수가 줄지 않는 것
we're seeing something where this doesn't particularly seem to be coming down.
같다는 거예요
It just seems to show a lot of volatility, um, representing the fact that some of the of the data
변동이 많은 것 같아요 추측 측면에서 일부 데이터 포인트가 다른
points are doing better than others in terms of the the guessing.
것보다 더 잘한다는 걸 보여주죠
But it's not as if there seems to be much of an improving trend or a trend in any direction yet.
하지만 아직 어떤 방향으로든 개선 추세가 있는 것 같진 않아요
Um, at least that's what appears to be the case.
적어도 겉으로 보기엔 그래요
So hopefully you are also running this, and you're going to be watching carefully to see what happens.
여러분도 이걸 실행하며 무슨 일이 일어나는지 주의 깊게 보시길 바라요
Uh, it's going to take a total, I think, of about 10 or 15 minutes to run all the way through, but
제 생각에는 다 실행하려면 10분에서 15분 정도 걸릴 것 같습니다
let's see where it is now in this list.
리스트의 어디에 있는지 보죠
We're now about halfway through.
이제 절반쯤 왔어요
When it gets to the end, there's going to be a pause while it goes through a step of validating the
끝에 다다르면 일시 정지가 됩니다 결과의 유효성을 확인하는 단계를
results and and and some, some confirmation checks on the OpenAI side that it that it tells you about
거치는 동안에요 OpenAI 쪽에서 확인을 합니다 상태에 대해 알려주는
in the, in the statuses.
부분이죠
Um, and then you actually get an email to tell you that it's completed at the same time as this run
Get이 완료됐다는 이메일을 받을 수 있어요 이 런이 완료되는 것과 동시에
completes.
말이죠
And when we pick up in the next video, it will have run.
다음 비디오에선 실행될 거예요
I will see you there.
거기서 봐요